export const LITERATUREINENGLISHA2009 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. A poem consisting of fourteen lines is",
A: "a narrative.",
B: "a sonnet.",
C: "an ode.",
D: "an elegy.",
answer: "B. sonnet.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The attitude of a writer towards the subject matter is the",
A: "tone.",
B: "plot.",
C: "crisis.",
D: "climax.",
answer: "A. tone.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The pattern of end rhymes in a poem is called",
A: "internal rhyme.",
B: "rhyme scheme.",
C: "rhythm.",
D: "scansion.",
answer: "B. rhyme scheme.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The most exciting and tense part of a story is the",
A: "epilogue.",
B: "climax",
C: "prologue.",
D: "exposition.",
answer: "B. climax.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Lines of unrhymed poetry are known as",
A: "blank verse.",
B: "assonance.",
C: "consonance.",
D: "free verse.",
answer: "D. free verse.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. A dramatic performance with only bodily movements and without words is",
A: "a mime.",
B: "an aside.",
C: "a soliloquy.",
D: "an opera.",
answer: "A. a mime.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. “Mathematics is my Achilles’ heel” is an example of",
A: "litotes",
B: "metonymy",
C: "allusion.",
D: "analogy.",
answer: "C. allusion. (Referring to Achilles' heel, a weakness)",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. A short poem lamenting the death of someone is a",
A: "Lyric",
B: "sonnet.",
C: "ballad.",
D: "threnody.",
answer: "D. threnody.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. In a story, the adversary of the protagonist is the",
A: "hero",
B: "heroine.",
C: "antagonist.",
D: "foil.",
answer: "C. antagonist.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. ‘Tell me not sweet, I am unkind” illustrates",
A: "inversion",
B: "paradox.",
C: "humour.",
D: "mood.",
answer: "A. inversion ('Tell me not sweet' inverts the normal word order)",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The art of giving human attributes to non-human objects is",
A: "personification.",
B: "allegory.",
C: "anecdote.",
D: "allusion.",
answer: "A. personification.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. A long narrative poem which deals with heroic deeds is",
A: "Lyric",
B: "Epic",
C: "Ode",
D: "Euphony",
answer: "B. Epic",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. A poem of four lines is called",
A: "quatrain.",
B: "sestet.",
C: "sonnet.",
D: "couplet.",
answer: "A. quatrain.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. A literary piece used to mock or ridicule a society or practice is called",
A: "an allegory.",
B: "a fable.",
C: "a farce.",
D: "a satire.",
answer: "D. a satire.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The story of a person’s life written by another is",
A: "history.",
B: "autobiography.",
C: "biography.",
D: "anthology.",
answer: "C. biography.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. When characters talk to each other, it is referred to as",
A: "Soliloquy.",
B: "monologue.",
C: "dialogue.",
D: "recitation.",
answer: "C. dialogue.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. A folktale is a",
A: "novel.",
B: "work of fiction.",
C: "biography.",
D: "novelette.",
answer: "B. work of fiction.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. A poem written in an elaborate style to address or celebrate an object or event is called",
A: "a ballad.",
B: "an epic.",
C: "a dirge.",
D: "an ode.",
answer: "D. an ode.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The dominant device in the above lines is",
A: "burlesque.",
B: "paradox.",
C: "conflict.",
D: "irony.",
answer: "C. Onomatopoeia ('buzzing,' 'humming,' 'clatter')",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The tone of the poem is one of",
A: "sorrow.",
B: "sarcasm.",
C: "happiness.",
D: "anger",
answer: "A. sorrow.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Kyeiwa is",
A: "relaxed.",
B: "ecstatic.",
C: "frightened.",
D: "elated.",
answer: "C. frightened.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The narrative technique is",
A: "third person.",
B: "a soliloquy.",
C: "first person.",
D: "an aside.",
answer: "A. third person.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The passage is",
A: "expository.",
B: "argumentative.",
C: "narrative.",
D: "analytical.",
answer: "C. narrative.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The atmosphere in the passage is one of",
A: "love.",
B: "fear.",
C: "Anger",
D: "joy.",
answer: "B. fear.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. ‘The little vehicle laps up the distance” conveys the impression of",
A: "leisure.",
B: "pleasure.",
C: "strength.",
D: "speed.",
answer: "D. speed.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The poem is about",
A: "war.",
B: "dirt.",
C: "travelling.",
D: "prison life.",
answer: "D. prison life.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The imagery in the first four lines is predominantly",
A: "agricultural.",
B: "military.",
C: "political.",
D: "social.",
answer: "B. military. (army tanks, fighter planes)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. “……a thousand miles” is an example of",
A: "hyperbole",
B: "irony",
C: "antithesis",
D: "epigram",
answer: "A. hyperbole ('a thousand miles')",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The poem is written in",
A: "blank verse.",
B: "pentameter.",
C: "free verse.",
D: "trochee.",
answer: "C. free verse. (No consistent meter or rhyme scheme)",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The impression created of the persona is one of",
A: "anger",
B: "competitiveness",
C: "reconciliation.",
D: "resignation.",
answer: "D. resignation.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The speaker is",
A: "Polonius.",
B: "Reynaldo.",
C: "Rosencrantz.",
D: "Laertes.",
answer: "A. Polonius.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The character being addressed is",
A: "Ophelia.",
B: "Hamlet.",
C: "Marcellus.",
D: "Bernado.",
answer: "A. Ophelia.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The subject of discussion is",
A: "Horatio.",
B: "Hamlet.",
C: "Marcellus.",
D: "Bernado.",
answer: "B. Hamlet.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The speaker is",
A: "happy.",
B: "confused.",
C: "excited.",
D: "anxious.",
answer: "D. anxious.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Thews and bulk means",
A: "power.",
B: "body and soul.",
C: "strength and size.",
D: "brain.",
answer: "C. strength and size.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Speaker X is",
A: "Horatio.",
B: "Marcellus.",
C: "Hamlet.",
D: "Laertes.",
answer: "B. Marcellus.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Speaker Y is",
A: "Bernado.",
B: "Francisco.",
C: "Polonius.",
D: "Rosencrantz.",
answer: "A. Bernado.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Tis gone and will not answer refers to the",
A: "grave digger.",
B: "ghost.",
C: "servant.",
D: "soldier.",
answer: "B. ghost.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The atmosphere is",
A: "frightening.",
B: "peaceful.",
C: "relaxed.",
D: "bleak.",
answer: "A. frightening.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The setting is",
A: "another part of the platform.",
B: "a platform in front of the castle.",
C: "the queen’s palace.",
D: "a room in the castle.",
answer: "B. a platform in front of the castle.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. the speaker is",
A: "the king",
B: "Laertes",
C: "the queen.",
D: "Polonius.",
answer: "D. Polonius.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. After this speech, the speaker",
A: "exits.",
B: "dies.",
C: "wakes up.",
D: "sleeps",
answer: "A. exits.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The character being addressed is",
A: "Laertes.",
B: "Hamlet.",
C: "Polonius.",
D: "Ophelia.",
answer: "D. Ophelia.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Another character present on the scene is’",
A: "Rosencrantz.",
B: "Guildenstern.",
C: "Polonius.",
D: "Hamlet.",
answer: "C. Polonius.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. The wildness referred to can also be called",
A: "loyal madness.",
B: "happiness.",
C: "Happiness",
D: "Death",
answer: "A. loyal madness. (Polonius hopes Ophelia's beauty will distract Hamlet from his melancholy)",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Speaker H is",
A: "Fortunbras.",
B: "Horatio",
C: "Osric.",
D: "Ambassador.",
answer: "B. Horatio.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. Speaker I is",
A: "Horatio.",
B: "Claudius.",
C: "Hamlet.",
D: "Osric.",
answer: "A. Horatio.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. sight refers to",
A: "players and drummers.",
B: "soldiers from England.",
C: "Incest committed",
D: "dead bodies.",
answer: "D. dead bodies.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. Shortly before this speech Died",
A: "the king",
B: "the queen",
C: "Hamlet",
D: "Polonius",
answer: "C. Hamlet",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Other characters who died earlier were",
A: "the quell and the ambassador.",
B: "Hamlet and Osric.",
C: "Ophelia and Horatio.",
D: "Laertes and the king.",
answer: "D. Laertes and the king.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Kyeiwa is",
A: "relaxed.",
B: "ecstatic.",
C: "frightened.",
D: "elated.",
answer: "C. frightened.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The narrative technique is",
A: "third person.",
B: "a soliloquy.",
C: "first person.",
D: "an aside.",
answer: "A. third person.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The passage is",
A: "expository.",
B: "argumentative.",
C: "narrative.",
D: "analytical.",
answer: "C. narrative.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The atmosphere in the passage is one of",
A: "love.",
B: "fear.",
C: "Anger",
D: "joy.",
answer: "B. fear.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. ‘The little vehicle laps up the distance” conveys the impression of",
A: "leisure.",
B: "pleasure.",
C: "strength.",
D: "speed.",
answer: "D. speed.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The poem is about",
A: "war.",
B: "dirt.",
C: "travelling.",
D: "prison life.",
answer: "D. prison life.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The imagery in the first four lines is predominantly",
A: "agricultural.",
B: "military.",
C: "political.",
D: "social.",
answer: "B. military. (army tanks, fighter planes)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. “……a thousand miles” is an example of",
A: "hyperbole",
B: "irony",
C: "antithesis",
D: "epigram",
answer: "A. hyperbole ('a thousand miles')",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The poem is written in",
A: "blank verse.",
B: "pentameter.",
C: "free verse.",
D: "trochee.",
answer: "C. free verse. (No consistent meter or rhyme scheme)",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The impression created of the persona is one of",
A: "anger",
B: "competitiveness",
C: "reconciliation.",
D: "resignation.",
answer: "D. resignation.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The speaker is",
A: "Polonius.",
B: "Reynaldo.",
C: "Rosencrantz.",
D: "Laertes.",
answer: "A. Polonius.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The character being addressed is",
A: "Ophelia.",
B: "Hamlet.",
C: "Marcellus.",
D: "Bernado.",
answer: "A. Ophelia.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The subject of discussion is",
A: "Horatio.",
B: "Hamlet.",
C: "Marcellus.",
D: "Bernado.",
answer: "B. Hamlet.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The speaker is",
A: "happy.",
B: "confused.",
C: "excited.",
D: "anxious.",
answer: "D. anxious.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Thews and bulk means",
A: "power.",
B: "body and soul.",
C: "strength and size.",
D: "brain.",
answer: "C. strength and size.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Speaker X is",
A: "Horatio.",
B: "Marcellus.",
C: "Hamlet.",
D: "Laertes.",
answer: "B. Marcellus.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Speaker Y is",
A: "Bernado.",
B: "Francisco.",
C: "Polonius.",
D: "Rosencrantz.",
answer: "A. Bernado.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Tis gone and will not answer refers to the",
A: "grave digger.",
B: "ghost.",
C: "servant.",
D: "soldier.",
answer: "B. ghost.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The atmosphere is",
A: "frightening.",
B: "peaceful.",
C: "relaxed.",
D: "bleak.",
answer: "A. frightening.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The setting is",
A: "another part of the platform.",
B: "a platform in front of the castle.",
C: "the queen’s palace.",
D: "a room in the castle.",
answer: "B. a platform in front of the castle.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. the speaker is",
A: "the king",
B: "Laertes",
C: "the queen.",
D: "Polonius.",
answer: "D. Polonius.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. After this speech, the speaker",
A: "exits.",
B: "dies.",
C: "wakes up.",
D: "sleeps",
answer: "A. exits.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The character being addressed is",
A: "Laertes.",
B: "Hamlet.",
C: "Polonius.",
D: "Ophelia.",
answer: "D. Ophelia.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Another character present on the scene is’",
A: "Rosencrantz.",
B: "Guildenstern.",
C: "Polonius.",
D: "Hamlet.",
answer: "C. Polonius.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. The wildness referred to can also be called",
A: "loyal madness.",
B: "happiness.",
C: "Happiness",
D: "Death",
answer: "A. loyal madness. (Polonius hopes Ophelia's beauty will distract Hamlet from his melancholy)",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Speaker H is",
A: "Fortunbras.",
B: "Horatio",
C: "Osric.",
D: "Ambassador.",
answer: "B. Horatio.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. Speaker I is",
A: "Horatio.",
B: "Claudius.",
C: "Hamlet.",
D: "Osric.",
answer: "A. Horatio.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. sight refers to",
A: "players and drummers.",
B: "soldiers from England.",
C: "Incest committed",
D: "dead bodies.",
answer: "D. dead bodies.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. Shortly before this speech Died",
A: "the king",
B: "the queen",
C: "Hamlet",
D: "Polonius",
answer: "C. Hamlet",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Other characters who died earlier were",
A: "the quell and the ambassador.",
B: "Hamlet and Osric.",
C: "Ophelia and Horatio.",
D: "Laertes and the king.",
answer: "D. Laertes and the king.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]